{
  "title": "Turkish Unit 1",
  "cards": [
    {
      "question": "merhaba",
      "answer": "hello"
    },
    {
      "question": "nasıl",
      "answer": "how"
    },
    {
      "question": "iyi",
      "answer": "good"
    },
    {
      "question": "iyiyim",
      "answer": "I'm fine"
    },
    {
      "question": "siz",
      "answer": "you"
    },
    {
      "question": "ben",
      "answer": "I"
    },
    {
      "question": "de",
      "answer": "too, also"
    },
    {
      "question": "adım",
      "answer": "my name"
    },
    {
      "question": "ad",
      "answer": "name"
    },
    {
      "question": "ne",
      "answer": "what"
    },
    {
      "question": "memnum oldum",
      "answer": "I'm pleased"
    },
    {
      "question": "adınız",
      "answer": "your name"
    },
    {
      "question": "sizin",
      "answer": "your"
    },
    {
      "question": "benim",
      "answer": "my"
    },
    {
      "question": "değil",
      "answer": "not"
    },
    {
      "question": "öyle mi?",
      "answer": "is that so? / really?"
    },
    {
      "question": "Türk",
      "answer": "Turkish (person)"
    },
    {
      "question": "milliyet",
      "answer": "nationality"
    },
    {
      "question": "milliyetiniz",
      "answer": "your nationality"
    },
    {
      "question": "İngiliz'im",
      "answer": "I'm English"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fransız",
      "answer": "French (person)"
    },
    {
      "question": "İngiliz",
      "answer": "English (person)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Londra",
      "answer": "London"
    },
    {
      "question": "Londralı",
      "answer": "Londoner"
    },
    {
      "question": "çok",
      "answer": "very, a lot, much, many"
    },
    {
      "question": "nederede",
      "answer": "where"
    },
    {
      "question": "memur",
      "answer": "officer, clerk"
    },
    {
      "question": "soyadı",
      "answer": "surname"
    },
    {
      "question": "soyadınız",
      "answer": "your surname"
    },
    {
      "question": "güzel",
      "answer": "beautiful, nice"
    },
    {
      "question": "Türkiye",
      "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
      "question": "öğretmen",
      "answer": "teacher"
    },
    {
      "question": "İngiltere",
      "answer": "England"
    },
    {
      "question": "ama",
      "answer": "but"
    },
    {
      "question": "öğrenci",
      "answer": "student"
    },
    {
      "question": "Türkçe",
      "answer": "Turkish (language)"
    },
    {
      "question": "bir",
      "answer": "a/an, one"
    },
    {
      "question": "harika",
      "answer": "wonderful"
    },
    {
      "question": "iş",
      "answer": "job, work"
    },
    {
      "question": "İngilizce",
      "answer": "English (language)"
    },
    {
      "question": "öğretmenim",
      "answer": "I'm a teacher"
    },
    {
      "question": "merhaba",
      "answer": "hello"
    },
    {
      "question": "selam",
      "answer": "hi"
    },
    {
      "question": "hoş geldiniz",
      "answer": "welcome"
    },
    {
      "question": "hoş bulduk",
      "answer": "thanks for your welcome"
    },
    {
      "question": "iyi günler",
      "answer": "have a nice day, good day"
    },
    {
      "question": "tünaydın",
      "answer": "good afternoon"
    },
    {
      "question": "iyi akşamlar",
      "answer": "good evening"
    },
    {
      "question": "iyi geceler",
      "answer": "good night"
    },
    {
      "question": "görüşürüz",
      "answer": "see you"
    },
    {
      "question": "sonra görüşürüz",
      "answer": "see you later"
    },
    {
      "question": "güle güle",
      "answer": "goodbye"
    },
    {
      "question": "allahaısmarladık",
      "answer": "goodbye"
    },
    {
      "question": "hoşça kal",
      "answer": "goodbye"
    },
    {
      "question": "anlamadım",
      "answer": "I don't understand"
    },
    {
      "question": "kendine iyi bak",
      "answer": "take care (of yourself)"
    },
    {
      "question": "nasılsınız",
      "answer": "how are you? (formal)"
    },
    {
      "question": "nasılsın",
      "answer": "how are you? (informal)"
    },
    {
      "question": "kusura bakma",
      "answer": "sorry (informal)"
    },
    {
      "question": "kusura bakmayin",
      "answer": "sorry (formal)"
    },
    {
      "question": "evet",
      "answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "hayır",
      "answer": "no"
    },
    {
      "question": "pardon",
      "answer": "excuse me"
    },
    {
      "question": "özür dilerim",
      "answer": "sorry, I apologize"
    },
    {
      "question": "affedersiniz",
      "answer": "excuse me"
    },
    {
      "question": "lütfen",
      "answer": "please"
    },
    {
      "question": "teşekkur ederim",
      "answer": "thank you"
    },
    {
      "question": "teşekkurler",
      "answer": "thanks (informal)"
    },
    {
      "question": "sağ ol",
      "answer": "thanks (very informal)"
    },
    {
      "question": "bir şey değil",
      "answer": "not at all, you're welcome"
    },
    {
      "question": "rica ederim",
      "answer": "not at all (very formal)"
    },
    {
      "question": "tamam",
      "answer": "OK / okay, all right"
    },
    {
      "question": "geçmiş olsun",
      "answer": "get well soon"
    },
    {
      "question": "iyi şanslar",
      "answer": "good luck"
    },
    {
      "question": "aferin",
      "answer": "well done"
    },
    {
      "question": "tebrikler",
      "answer": "congratulations"
    },
    {
      "question": "ne haber",
      "answer": "what's up?"
    },
    {
      "question": "selam söyle",
      "answer": "say hello"
    },
    {
      "question": "yalnız",
      "answer": "lonely, alone"
    },
    {
      "question": "doktor",
      "answer": "doctor"
    },
    {
      "question": "hasta",
      "answer": "sick, ill, patient"
    },
    {
      "question": "yorgun",
      "answer": "tired"
    },
    {
      "question": "profesör",
      "answer": "professor"
    },
    {
      "question": "Alman",
      "answer": "German"
    },
    {
      "question": "yarım elma",
      "answer": "half apple"
    },
    {
      "question": "yarım saat",
      "answer": "half an hour"
    },
    {
      "question": "yarım kilo",
      "answer": "half a kilo"
    },
    {
      "question": "çeyrek final",
      "answer": "quarter final"
    },
    {
      "question": "iki buçuk saat",
      "answer": "two and a half hours"
    },
    {
      "question": "dört buçuk kilo",
      "answer": "4 and a half kilos"
    },
    {
      "question": "bir buçuk porsiyon",
      "answer": "one and a half portions (servings)"
    },
    {
      "question": "iki buçuk",
      "answer": "two and a half"
    },
    {
      "question": "dört buçuk",
      "answer": "four and a half"
    },
    {
      "question": "kalem",
      "answer": "pencil"
    },
    {
      "question": "kalemler",
      "answer": "pencils"
    },
    {
      "question": "çicek",
      "answer": "flower"
    },
    {
      "question": "çiçekler",
      "answer": "flowers"
    },
    {
      "question": "bebek",
      "answer": "baby"
    },
    {
      "question": "bebekler",
      "answer": "babies"
    },
    {
      "question": "köpek",
      "answer": "dog"
    },
    {
      "question": "köpekler",
      "answer": "dogs"
    },
    {
      "question": "ev",
      "answer": "house/home"
    },
    {
      "question": "evler",
      "answer": "houses/homes"
    },
    {
      "question": "otel",
      "answer": "hotel"
    },
    {
      "question": "oteller",
      "answer": "hotels"
    },
    {
      "question": "fare",
      "answer": "mouse"
    },
    {
      "question": "fareler",
      "answer": "mice"
    },
    {
      "question": "sinek",
      "answer": "fly"
    },
    {
      "question": "sinekler",
      "answer": "flies"
    },
    {
      "question": "kitap",
      "answer": "book"
    },
    {
      "question": "kitaplar",
      "answer": "books"
    },
    {
      "question": "insan",
      "answer": "human"
    },
    {
      "question": "insanlar",
      "answer": "people"
    },
    {
      "question": "armut",
      "answer": "pear"
    },
    {
      "question": "armutlar",
      "answer": "pears"
    },
    {
      "question": "kuş",
      "answer": "bird"
    },
    {
      "question": "kuşlar",
      "answer": "birds"
    },
    {
      "question": "çocuk",
      "answer": "child"
    },
    {
      "question": "çocuklar",
      "answer": "children"
    },
    {
      "question": "at",
      "answer": "horse"
    },
    {
      "question": "atlar",
      "answer": "horses"
    },
    {
      "question": "kaz",
      "answer": "goose"
    },
    {
      "question": "kazlar",
      "answer": "geese"
    },
    {
      "question": "duvar",
      "answer": "wall"
    },
    {
      "question": "duvarlar",
      "answer": "walls"
    },
    {
      "question": "Türkler",
      "answer": "Turkish people"
    },
    {
      "question": "İngilizler",
      "answer": "English people"
    },
    {
      "question": "Almanlar",
      "answer": "German people"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fransızlar",
      "answer": "French people"
    },
    {
      "question": "paralar",
      "answer": "money"
    },
    {
      "question": "sular",
      "answer": "water"
    },
    {
      "question": "bilgi",
      "answer": "information"
    },
    {
      "question": "bilgiler",
      "answer": "information"
    },
    {
      "question": "kar",
      "answer": "snow"
    },
    {
      "question": "karlar",
      "answer": "snow"
    },
    {
      "question": "tuz",
      "answer": "salt"
    },
    {
      "question": "tuzlar",
      "answer": "salt"
    },
    {
      "question": "pantolon",
      "answer": "trousers"
    },
    {
      "question": "pantolonlar",
      "answer": "more than one pair of trousers"
    },
    {
      "question": "gözlük",
      "answer": "glasses"
    },
    {
      "question": "gözlükler",
      "answer": "more than one pair of glasses"
    },
    {
      "question": "makas",
      "answer": "scissors"
    },
    {
      "question": "makaslar",
      "answer": "more than one pair of scissors"
    },
    {
      "question": "çoğul",
      "answer": "plural"
    },
    {
      "question": "tatlı",
      "answer": "sweet"
    },
    {
      "question": "saat",
      "answer": "watch, clock, hour"
    },
    {
      "question": "protokol",
      "answer": "protocol"
    },
    {
      "question": "alkol",
      "answer": "alcohol"
    },
    {
      "question": "hakikat",
      "answer": "reality, truth, fact"
    },
    {
      "question": "harf",
      "answer": "letter (character)"
    },
    {
      "question": "dair",
      "answer": "related to, concerning"
    },
    {
      "question": "muayenehane",
      "answer": "doctor's surgery"
    },
    {
      "question": "daire",
      "answer": "circle, apartment"
    },
    {
      "question": "maalesef",
      "answer": "unfortunately"
    },
    {
      "question": "maaş",
      "answer": "salary, wage"
    },
    {
      "question": "müsaade",
      "answer": "permission"
    },
    {
      "question": "fiil",
      "answer": "verb"
    },
    {
      "question": "aile",
      "answer": "family"
    },
    {
      "question": "tabii",
      "answer": "of course, natural"
    }
  ]
}
